<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on René Reitmann</title>
    <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on René Reitmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 17:20:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rreitmann.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Magicline (February 2022 - June 2022)</title>
      <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/magicline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 17:20:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/magicline/</guid>
      <description>As a backend developer in the team &amp;ldquo;Digital Distribution&amp;rdquo; of the Magicline I was part of a 6-member international and cross-functional team which was responsible for making the Magicline available to end customers both on a test basis and in the further process for a fee. The goal was to automate the process as much as possible and to simplify the familiarization with the Magicline so that the end customers can start using the Magicline on their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadatamagement (April 2015 - December 2021)</title>
      <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/metadatamagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 17:20:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/metadatamagement/</guid>
      <description>As a member of the DZHW I was part of a 5 person team as Scrum Master, Full Stack Developer and DevOp that developed a search portal for social science research data. Currently, this portal is being further developed and operated. The entire development process takes place openly at GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Order and Transport Management (January 2011 - November 2011)</title>
      <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/global-order-and-transport-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 13:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/global-order-and-transport-management/</guid>
      <description>As an employee of Zühlke Engineering, I was one of 10 architects involved in the development of the central system for the worldwide processing of transport orders for a logistics service provider. About 100 people worked on the entire development project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing in Digital Road Maps as SaaS (June 2010 - December 2010)</title>
      <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/routing-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 15:35:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/routing-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>As an employee of Zühlke Engineering I was involved as a software engineer in the development of a service for calculating optimal routes in digital road maps. The automation of acceptance tests with SoapUI was also one of my tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Order Management at a Postal Service Provider (January 2006 - February 2010)</title>
      <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/easymail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 16:36:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/easymail/</guid>
      <description>As an employee of Capgemini I was initially involved as software developer and later as architect in the further development of the order management system of a German postal service provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composing Web Services with BPEL (November 2004 - March 2005)</title>
      <link>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/virtusa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 16:57:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rreitmann.github.io/project/virtusa/</guid>
      <description>In this internship at Virtusa in Sri Lanka I dealt with the topic SOA and web services. I was part of an R&amp;amp;D team and developed a proof-of-concept for composing web services with BPEL. Here I mapped a small internal team process. I passed on the findings of this PoC in tech talks to the company&amp;rsquo;s employees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>